Pretty Little Liars 지난 이야기
Previously
on Pretty Little Liars.
앨리의 시신이 발견됐어
They found Ali's body.
나는 여전히 여기 있어, 개년들아
- (mobile phone ringing)
- I'm here still here, bitches.
ALL:
And I know everything.
그리고 모든 것을 알고 있어
앨리슨
Alison.
그녀는 살아있고
나는 증명할 수 있어요
She is alive and I can prove it.
앨리슨이 살아 있다구요?
Alison is alive?
(door opens)
놀라운 일이네요
Surprise.
현금, 여권 그리고 비행기표야
The cash, passport
and plane ticket,
넌 한 시간 내로
공항으로 가야 해
you need to leave
for the airport in an hour.
A가 누구인지 알아낼 때까진
난 집에 갈 수 없어
Until I know who "A" is,
I can't come home.
네가 죽었다고
A가 생각하게끔 만들어야 해
Let "A" think you're dead.
모나는 나를 바보로 만들었어
Mona played me like a fool.
그녀가 원했던대로 된 거지
She got exactly what she wanted.
에즈라는 여전히
나를 찾고 있어, 아리아
Ezra's still looking
for me, Aria.
그는 나를 구해낸다면
너를 되찾을 거라 생각해
He thinks that if he saves me,
he'll win you back.
거래를 하고 싶은 거라면...
If you're looking
to make a deal...
앨리슨 딜로렌티스라고 생각했던,
I know who killed that girl,
the one you thought
was Alison DiLaurentis.
그 소녀를 누가 죽였는지 알아요
알리, 도망가!
Ali, run!
이봐, 이봐, 네가 누군지 알아
Hey, hey, I know who you are.
(gunshot)
안 돼
No.
미안해
I'm sorry.
쉬
Shh.
(siren wailing)
맥박이 약해지고 있어
His pulse is getting weaker.
나 좀 가게해 줘, 제발
Hey, let me go, please.
총소리를 듣곤
옥상으로 뛰어 올라갔죠
I heard a gunshot
and I ran up to the roof.
거기 갔을 때
그 사람은 바닥에 누워 있었어요
But when I got there,
he was lying on the ground.
아리아, 당장 우리가
에즈라를 도와줄 것이 없어
Aria, we cannot do anything
to help him right now.
네가 이 일에 대해 안다고
경찰이 생각하면
If they think you know
anything about this,
you're gonna spend
the entire night
넌 밤새도록
answering questions
at the police station.
경찰서에서 질문에 답해야 해
넌 절대 병원에 가선 안 돼
You're never gonna get
to the hospital.
Spencer's right.
스펜서 말이 맞아
에즈라를 어디로 데려 갔는지 알아내서
We'll find out
where they're taking him
and we'll get you there.
우리가 데려다 줄게
Folks, could you
step back please?
여러분, 물러나 주시겠습니까?
(siren wailing)
♪ Got a secret ♪
Pretty Little Liars S05 X E01
Escape From New York (뉴욕에서 탈출하기)
♪ Can you keep it? ♪
♪ Swear this one you'll save ♪
♪ Better lock it
in your pocket ♪
♪ Taking this one to the grave ♪
♪ If I show you
then I know you ♪
한글 자막 적과의 동침
♪ Won't tell what I said ♪
♪ Cause two can keep a secret ♪
미드나잇 / DC 인사이드 기미갤
♪ If one of them is dead ♪
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com
우선적인 환자가 있다
20대 중반 남성으로
PARAMEDIC: Priority one.
Mid-20s, male.
복부에 총상이 있다
Single GSW to the abdomen.
혈압은 142
수축 혈압은 80이예요
Last pulse was 142.
Systolic 80.
(indistinct chatter)
탈장상태예요
수술실로 데려가요
He's herniating.
Get him to the OR.
뭐라고 말 해야 하는지 알지?
SPENCER: You know
what to say, right?
해야 할 말 보다
오래 통화 하지 마
Don't stay on the line a second
longer than you have to.
여기서 파는 것 중에
이게 가장 강한 거야
It's the strongest one they had.
이걸 정말 하고 싶은 거야?
Are you sure
you want to do this?
Ezra just saved my life.
에즈라는 내 목숨을 살렸어
그리고 너희들 역시 살린걸 거야
And he probably
saved yours, too.
Hanna's right.
한나의 말이 맞아
우리 엄마는
그렇게 점프를 할 순 없어
There's no way
my mom made that jump.
엄마는 A가 아니지만
에즈라는 A가 누군지 알아
She's not "A."
But Ezra knows who is.
엠, 계획은 오늘 밤에
알리를 이 곳에서 탈출시키는 거였지만
Look, Em, the plan was to
get Ali out of town tonight,
but now that we know
that "A's" after Ezra...
이젠 A가 에즈라를
쫓고 있다는 걸 알고 있고...
A는 에즈라가 입을 다물길
원한다는 건 알겠어
I get that "A" wants
to shut Ezra up,
좋아, 하지만
알리는 여전히 타겟이야
okay, but Ali's still a target.
우리가 다른 방법을
찾아 볼 순 없을까?
Can't we think
of another way to do this?
만약 에즈라가...
If Ezra...
when Ezra pulls through,
에즈라가 깨어나면
he's going to tell us
who "A" is,
A가 누구인지
우리에게 말해 줄 거고
and this thing
is finally gonna be over.
그러면 이 일은
드디어 끝나게 되는 거야
HANNA: Hi, the guy
who just got shot
여보세요, 뱅크 앤 허드슨에서
총에 맞은 에즈라 핏츠라는
사람에 관한 일이예요
at Bank and Hudson is Ezra Fitz.
네, 병원에 경찰을
보내야 한다고 생각해요
Yeah, I think that
you should send a cop
to the hospital
because I saw what happened,
어떤 일이 있었는지
제가 목격했고
이 일이 마구잡이로
생긴 일이 아니기 때문이죠
and I don't think
this was a random thing.
Well, yeah,
but he might not be safe
네, 하지만, 그 사람이
위험할 수도 있으니
so you better go fast.
빨리 경찰을 불러야 해요
Are they sending somebody?
병원에 누군가를 보내겠대?
Yeah, I heard her typing.
응, 타이핑 소리를 들었어
Look, they're probably
on their way.
아마도 그 사람들이
처리를 할 거야
Are we sure that
we want to split up?
우리가 정말
갈라지길 원하는 거야?
A wise commander takes measures
현명한 지휘관은
항상 그의 적을
안좋은 상황으로 몰아가도록
to always let his opponent react
to the wrong
set of circumstances.
조치를 취하는 거야
And in 400 BC...
기원전 400년엔...
Okay, Spencer, we get it.
We're decoys.
알았어, 스펜서, 우린 알았다구
우린 바람잡이야
역사 수업은 필요 없다구
이 전쟁에 병법은 없어, 스펜서
There's no art
to this war, Spencer.
You've read Sun Tzu?
손자병법 읽어 봤니?
ARIA: Okay, let's go.
좋아, 가자
HANNA: Wait.
기다려 봐
Just in case.
만일을 대비해서
We'll give you 10 minutes, okay,
10분을 줄 거야
그리고 우리가 전화를 할 거야
and then we're making the call.
엠, 가자
Em, come on.
Look, if you want to get
to the hospital before them,
그들 보다 먼저
병원에 도착하려면
we have to go now.
당장 출발해야 돼
We know that "A" is always
one step ahead of us.
언제나 A가 우리보다
한 발 앞선다는 걸 우린 알고 있어
그래
Yeah.
아마도 그건, 그녀건, 무엇이건,
그 개같은 A는 그랬지
Maybe he, she, it, bitch is.
But you have to remember that.
하지만 넌 기억해야 해
Ali's been hiding
in plain sight for two years.
알리는 2년 동안
찾기 쉬운 곳에 숨어 있었다는 걸
She can handle herself.
알리는 스스로 처신할 수 있었어
그리고 병원에서
A가 우리를 먼저 본다면
And if "A" sees us there first,
then this could work.
이건 성공할 수 있을 거야
확인 전화 줘서 고마워요, 애쉴리
Thank you
for checking in, Ashley.
오늘 밤엔 누구도
한 숨도 못 잘 거니까
Nobody's getting
any sleep here tonight,
so don't hesitate to call
if you hear from Hanna.
한나로 부터 연락이 온다면
주저말고 전화주세요
그럼요
우리도 그렇게 할게요
Of course.
We'll do the same.
Bye.
끊을게요
앨리슨이 살아 있다는 걸
스펜서는 지금껏 알고 있었단 건가요?
All this time Spencer knew
Alison was alive?
믿고 싶지 않지만
I don't want to believe that,
그것이 사실이라면
because if that's true,
난 네 동생이 어떤 애인지
알 수가 없구나
I have no idea
who your sister is.
한 달 전에 찍힌,
앨리슨이 그 아이들과 함께 있는 사진을
The photograph that
Detective Holbrook showed me
of the girls with Alison
was taken a month ago.
홀브룩 형사가 보여 줬어
I want to think that that was
the first time they saw her,
그 때가 아이들이 앨리슨을
처음 본 거라 생각한다
because it makes sense,
그건 이해가 되기 때문이지
that's when it all
started again.
그 때 모든 것이
다시 시작됐거든
The pills?
그 약 문제 말인가요?
약 그리고 거짓말
The pills and the lying.
It was just like last time
Spencer was out of control.
그 때가 스펜서가 통제력을 잃었던
마지막 이었지
It's so like
Ali to do this to her.
알리가 스펜서를
그렇게 만든 것 같아요
얘야, 앨리슨이 어디에 있었는지
Honey, we don't know
anything about
어떤 일이 있었는지
우린 아무것도 알지 못 해
where Alison's been
or what she's gone through.
아직 판단하지 않으려 한다
I'm trying to reserve judgment.
엄마, 앨리슨이
모든 문제의 중심이었고
Mom, Alison was
at the center of every mess
that Spencer got into.
스펜서가 말려 들어간 거예요
앨리슨은 걸어다니는 폭탄이었지만
She's a walking time bomb,
but it's never Ali who blows up.
폭발해 버린건
앨리슨이 결코 아니었어요
It's everything and
everyone else around her.
그 아이 주변의 모든 것들과
모든 사람들이었어요
도망치는 건 이해해요
I understand running away.
하지만 엄마는 친구들과
가족들을 믿게 할 수 있나요?
But to let your
friends and family think
엄마가 죽었다구요?
you're dead?
나는 믿었다구요
그게 앨리슨의 무덤이라고
It was Alison in that grave.
우린 모두 그랬지
We all did.
하지만 그 사진을 봤고
But I saw that picture
앨리슨은 매우 생기가 있더구나
and she's very much alive.
난 앨리슨을 위해
울어주진 않겠어요
I'm not crying for Alison.
자신의 딸을 잃어버린
다른 가정이 있다구요
There is another family
missing their daughter.
And she really is dead.
그리고 그 아이는
정말로 죽었구요
그 소녀가 누구인지는
경찰이 알아내겠지
The police will find out
who that girl is.
그건 시간 문제일 뿐이야
It's just a matter of time.
Mom...
엄마...
there's something
you need to know.
아셔야 할 일이 있어요
(car door slams)
(doorbell rings)
에즈라가 어떻게
우리를 찾았는지 모르겠어
I don't understand
how Ezra found us.
그가 우리를 찾은 게 아닐 거야
Maybe he didn't find us.
A를 쫓아온 거였다고 생각해
I think he was
following "A."
그리고 A는
우리를 쫓아온 거고
And "A" was following us.
이게 네가 항상
두려워 했던 일이야
This is what you were
always so afraid of.
우리가 A에게 널 이끈거지
That we'd lead "A" to you.
아리아, 왜 아직도 에즈라가
나를 찾는지 알잖아
Aria, you know why Ezra's
still looking for me.
널 되찾고 싶어하기 때문이야
It's 'cause he wants
to win you back.
Does he have a chance?
에즈라에게 기회가 있니?
알리, 지금은
그걸 생각할 수 없어
Ali, I can't think
about that right now.
I don't even know if he's alive.
그가 살 수 있을지 조차 모르는 걸
I wanted to tell you in person
오늘 밤, 경찰 구류를 탈출한
that CeCe Drake escaped
police custody tonight.
씨씨 드레이크라는 사람에 대해
말하러 왔습니다
우린 마을 외곽 도로에서
의식을 잃은
We found Officer
Maple unconscious
메이플 경관을 발견했죠
on a road outside of town.
아직까지 우리는 씨씨와
So far we have not been able
경관의 순찰차가
어디에 있는지 알 수 없습니다
to locate CeCe
or his patrol car.
I don't understand why you
came here to tell us this.
왜 당신이 여기에 와서
우리에게 이런 얘기를 하는지 이해할 수 없군요
씨씨는 앨리슨이
살아 있다는 걸 알고 있고
CeCe knows that Alison is alive
앨리슨이 어디 있는지
알고 있다고 생각합니다
and I think she knows
where the girls are.
만약 씨씨가 이 일과 관련이 있다면
If she's mixed up in this,
당신의 딸은
이전 보다 더 위험할 겁니다
your daughter could be
in more danger than ever.
따라서 당신들이 알고 있는 걸
So if there's anything
that you haven't told me...
말해 준다면...
우리가 알고 있는 모든 건
당신에게 말했소
We've told you everything
that we know.
경찰은 로즈우드에서 실종된
REPORTER: (on TV) Police
have also widened their search
for the four missing
Rosewood teens
4명의 소녀들의
수색 범위를 확대했습니다
소녀들은 필라델피아에서
앨리슨 딜로렌티스와
who they believe
are in Philadelphia
함께 있는 것으로 믿고 있습니다
with Alison DiLaurentis.
The youth went
missing two years ago
앨리슨은 2년 전에 실종돼
잔인하게 살해된 것으로 알려졌으나...
and is thought to have been
brutally murdered...
This changes everything.
이제 모든 게 변했어
파편이 너무 많아
There's a ton of debris in here.
나 좀 도와야 겠어
I need hands.
출혈이 너무 심해
He's losing too much blood.
동맥을 꽉 쥐어
Clamp that artery.
당장
Now.
알겠습니다
Okay.
(rapid beeping)
I'm doing my part,
Mr. Fitz.
나의 일을 할 겁니다, 핏츠 씨
You got to do yours.
당신의 일을 하세요
내 앞에서 죽지 말아요
Don't die on me.
여기야
This way.
가자
Let's go.
자, 이제 뭘 해야 하지?
Okay, now what do we do?
기다려야지
We wait.
안녕하세요, 우린 좀 전에 실려온
Hi, we are looking for a patient
that was just
admitted, Ezra Fitz?
에즈라 핏츠를 찾고 있어요
이 짓 하기 싫다
I hate this.
그저 잘 되길 바라자구
Let's just hope it works.
앨리슨 딜로렌티스 씨
WOMAN: (on P.A.)
Alison DiLaurentis,
응급실로 와서
서류를 작성해 주세요
please report
to the Emergency Room.
엘리슨 딜로렌티스 씨
응급실로 와서 서류를 작성해 주세요
Alison DiLaurentis report
to the Emergency Room.
시작됐다. 리더를 따르라
__
넌 나가 있는 게 낫겠어
Okay, you better
get out of here.
계단이야!
Stairs!
(siren wailing)
택시!
WOMAN: Taxi!
(tires screeching)
(honking)
야!
MAN: Hey!
(saxophone music playing)
(metal clanking)
놀아 보자고?
(whispering) Want to play?
끝났어
It's over.
No. It's not.
아니. 그렇지 않아
Did you really think
we'd let Ali
정말로 우리가 알리를
leave that hospital alone?
병원에 홀로 둘 거라 생각한 거야?
We paged Alison so you'd
know she was there.
앨리슨을 찾는 안내 방송을 하게 해서
네가 알도록 한 거야
I guess you don't read
Sun Tzu, bitch.
손자 병법을 읽지 않았구만, 개년아
이봐!
Hey!
(gasping)
그게 A라고 믿는 거야?
Are you sure that's "A"?
아마도 내가 A 지롱!
Maybe I'm "A"!
아니면 저들 중 하나일지도
Or maybe it's one of them.
Maybe I'm "A".
(laughter)
(siren wailing)
이봐, 친구들
당장 흩어 지라구
All right, folks,
we need you to disperse now.
A는 우리보다 한 발 앞섰어
"A" was one step ahead of us.
적어도 에즈라로 부터
A는 떨어 뜨렸잖아
At least we got
"A" away from Ezra.
여기서 빠져 나가자
Let's get out of here.
핏츠제랄드 부인
NURSE:
Mrs. Fitzgerald.
총알은 성공적으로 제거했지만
We've successfully
removed the bullet
동맥 손상이 광범위합니다
but arterial
damage is extensive.
네, 그렇죠
Yes, that's right.
네
NURSE: Yes.
넌 이 옥탑에서 지내야 돼
You need to stay on top of this.
우린 모일거야
We're mobilizing.
그들은 필라델피아에 있지 않고...
They're not in Philadelphia...
뉴욕에 있어
they're in New York.
여기에 더 많은 사람들이
있을 거라고 했잖아
You said there'd be
more people here.
그들은 올거야
They're coming.
놀랐잖아요
You scared me.
더이상 비밀로 할 수 없어요
I can't keep this
a secret anymore.
홀브룩 형사에게
사실을 말하겠어요
I want to tell
Holbrook the truth.
스펜서가 알게 되면
When Spencer finds out,
집에 올 이유가 된다구요
she'll have
a reason to come home.
네가 나에게 말한 걸
네 엄마가 절대 알아선 안 돼
Your mother can never know
what you told me.
(phone ringing)
홀브룩 입니다
This is Holbrook.
뉴욕 경찰서의
형사로부터 전화 왔습니다
WOMAN: A detective
from the NYPD is on the line.
연결해 주세요
Put him through.
오늘밤에 우리는
해야 할 일이 많습니다
We've got a lot
going on here tonight.
무얼 도와드리면 되죠?
What can I help you with?
뉴욕의 총기사건이
우리와 무슨 관련입니까?
Why would a shooting
in New York involve us?
에즈라 핏츠
알겠습니다, 그를 조사해 보고
답신을 드리겠습니다
Okay, I'll look into him
and get back to you.
감사합니다
Thank you.
그 개놈을 놓친 건 아쉽지만
I'm sorry you lost that bitch,
너희들이 여기에서
A를 쫓아낸 거야
but you did get "A" out of here.
에즈라의 수술은 어때?
Is Ezra out of surgery?
병원에서 에즈라 엄마에게
총알은 제거됐다고
I heard them tell Ezra's mom
that the bullet
말하는 걸 들었어
traveled up and hit...
에즈라 엄마는 비행기에 오를 거지만
지금 시드니에 있어
She's getting on a plane,
but she's in Sydney.
그리고 여기에 그를 위한 사람은
나 밖에 없어
And there's nobody here
for him but me.
우리가 거기에 가길 원하니?
HANNA: Do you want us
to come there?
아니
No.
아냐, 아직은
내가 여기에 섞여 있을게
No, so far I'm blending in,
우리 다섯이 함께 있는 건
but I think with the five of us,
위험에 빠뜨리는 거라구
it might be waving a red flag.
수술을 했기 때문에
Once he's out of surgery,
에즈라가 깨어나는데
몇 시간을 걸릴 거야
it's still gonna take him
a few hours to wake up.
우린 가 있을 만한 곳을
찾아 봐야 겠다
We need to find somewhere to go.
뭔가 듣게 되는대로
전화해 줘
Call us as soon
as you hear anything.
그럴게
I will.
Guys, promise me you'll be safe.
얘들아, 너희들 안전할 거라고
내게 약속해 줘
우리 걱정은 마, 아리아
Don't worry about us, Aria.
우린 괜찮을 거야
약속할게
We'll be okay.
We promise.
끊을게
Bye.
A가 에즈라를 처리하지 못 한다면
If "A" can't get to Ezra,
네가 오늘밤 타겟이 될거야
you're the available
target tonight.
그래, 엠이 맞아
Yeah, Em's right.
우린 이렇게 길거리에서
Mean, we can't
just stand out here
앉아 있을 수 만은 없다구...
in the street like sitting...
오리처럼 말이야
ducks.
우리가 갈 만한 곳을 알아
I know a place we can go.
따라 와
Come on.
Well...
세상에...
와우하는 순간과 함께
누군가에게 감명을 주고 싶다면
If you wanted to impress
someone with a "wow" moment,
this would definitely be
how you'd do it.
이게 분명 그렇게 할 수 있을 거야
그는 나에게 감동을 주기위해
여기에 데려오지 않았어
He didn't bring me here
to impress me.
여기는 그의 특별한 공간이었어
This was kind
of his special place.
So you know somebody
who works here?
그럼 여기서 일하는
사람을 아는 거예요?
음, 그래, 가족의 친구지
Uh, yeah, a friend
of the family.
극장에 데려가겠다고
Well, when you said that
you were gonna take me
to the theater,
말했을 때
연극을 보여주려는 건지 알았죠
I thought you meant
to see a play.
실망했니?
Are you disappointed?
Wow.
와우
I get it.
알 것 같아요
Get what?
뭘 알아?
It's hard to explain.
설명하기 힘들어요
Try me.
설명해 봐
God, imagine being up here,
신은, 저 위에 있다고 생각하지만
with all those people
out there who love you.
당신을 사랑하는 사람들과
함께 있는 거예요
I think that's called
adoration, not love.
그건 사랑이 아니라
경배라고 생각해
I could be an actress.
난 여배우가 될 수 있을지도 몰라요
Could be?
그럴 수 있을지도?
Well, I hate to break it to you
글쎄, 네 생각을
깨고 싶진 않지만
넌 이미 해낸 거야
but you already are.
The way you tell your stories
넌 너의 이야기를 할 때
그런 확신이 있어
such conviction.
자신을 믿는다면
I think you've
convinced yourself
그것들의 절반은
사실이라고 생각해
that half of them are true.
스스로를 믿지 못한다면
Well, if you can't
convince yourself,
why should
anyone else believe you?
사람들이 어떻게
당신을 믿겠어요?
You really are my
Holly Golightly.
넌 정말 나의 홀리 고라이틀리야
누구요?
- Who?
- (Door closes)
여기 허락받은 거 확실해요?
Are you sure
we're allowed to be here?
Who's there?
거기 누구요?
Oh, I'm sorry,
Mr. Fitzgerald.
오, 미안해요, 핏츠제럴드 씨
My apologies.
사과할게요
I was just locking up
on my way out.
막 나가려고 문을 잠갔었거든요
No, don't worry about it, Bill.
아뇨, 신경쓰지 마세요, 빌
Have a good night.
좋은 밤 되세요
Okay, good night.
네, 좋은 밤 되세요
Mr. Fitzgerald?
핏츠제랄드 씨라구요?
That's when I realized
Ezra was a rich boy
그때 난, 에즈라가
가난한 척 하지만
부유한 사람이란 걸 알았지
pretending to be a poor boy.
I actually liked him
more for that.
사실 그것 때문에
그가 더 좋았지
그가 돈을 원하지 않았기 때문이 아니라
Not because he didn't
want the money,
but because
he totally had me fooled.
나를 완전히
바보로 만들어 버렸기 때문에
I actually thought
that was an asset back then.
그땐 정말로 그게
중요하다고 생각했었지
와우
Wow.
이거 진짜 총이네
This is a real gun.
한나!
Hanna!
So you think we'll be
okay here until morning?
그래서 넌 우리가
아침까지 여기 있어도 괜찮다고 생각해?
I've stayed over a few times.
몇 번 여기에 왔었어
They don't open up
the place until noon.
정오까지는 문 열지 않아
(stomach rumbling)
그게 뭔 소리야?
What was that?
TOGETHER:
Spencer's stomach.
스펜서의 배에서
미안, 신부의 쇼에서
후식 케익 4개 먹은 후로
Sorry, I haven't had
anything to eat
since a petit four
at the bridal show.
아무 것도 먹지 못했잖아
따라 와, 구내 매점을 뒤져 보자
Come on, let's raid
the concession stand.
아직 먹을 것이
남아 있다는 거야?
You think that it's still
gonna be stocked?
Spence, we need
to get you some food.
스펜서, 우린 네게
먹을 걸 좀 줘야 해
I'm literally at the point
where I cannot think.
난 말 그대로
생각도 할 수 없는 지경이라구
음, 단백질 대신에 너티 츄스를
Well, I guess Nutty Chews
can count as a protein
and Gummy Bears as a fruit.
그리고 과일 대신에 구미 베어즈로 해야 겠네
상관 없어, 너무 배 고파서
I don't care, I was so hungry
그 의자 쿠션의
고무까지 먹어버릴 참이었으니까
I was about to eat the foam
out of those seat cushions.
I saw that episode.
나 그 에피소드 봤어
Me, too.
나두
그 숙녀가 일 년동안
세 명의 코치들과의 경험담이지
That lady went through
three couches in a year.
What show is this?
그게 무슨 TV 쇼 였는데?
Freaky Foodies.
기이한 음식들
Have you seen it?
그거 봤니?
Spencer's obsessed.
스펜서가 집착이 있잖아
What and you're not?
뭐라, 니들은 안 그랬어?
We watch that
entire marathon together.
우린 함께 그 쇼를 정주행 했잖아
Oh, my God, remember that guy
who ate the dryer sheets?
세상에, 그 마른 종이 먹은 남자 기억나?
Ew, that was so gross.
웩, 그건 정말 역겨웠어
I need to find a better place
to make a call.
통화하기 더 나은
장소를 찾아야 겠어
Who do you need to talk to?
전화할 사람이 있어?
I have a few friends
that are gonna be worried now
내가 살아 있다는 걸
경찰이 알게 되서
지금 걱정하고 있을
몇몇 친구들이 있어
that the police know I'm alive.
They've risked a lot to help me,
그들은 나를 돕기 위해
많은 위험을 감수해왔고
I just need to let them know
that I'm okay.
내가 무사하다는 것을
알려 줘야 해
I'll be right back.
바로 돌아올게
여보세요
Hello.
그래, 나야
ALI: Yeah, it's me.
(Ali talking very quietly)
Shana?
샤나?
Ali sent me
to make sure you're okay.
네가 괜찮은지
알리가 날 보냈어
Look, I get that
you're her loyal companion,
네가 알리의
충실한 친구인건 알겠는데
but I don't need a watchdog.
난 감시자는 필요 없어
나처럼 할 필요는 없어, 아리아
You don't have to like me, Aria.
하지만 난 약속을 했고
그래서 여기 있을 거야
But I made a promise,
so I'm staying.
Can I get you something?
- 뭐 필요한 거 있어?
- 아니. 괜찮아
No. Thanks.
You look exhausted.
피곤해 보인다
Don't worry.
걱정하지 마
네가 잠이 들면
내가 깨워줄게
If you fall asleep,
I'll wake you up
어떤 소식이 있다면 말이야
if there's any news.
난 괜찮아
I'm fine.
알리가 다시 우리를
배제하고 있다고
SPENCER: Is it just me
or does it already feel like
나만 그러는 거야,
아님 이미 느끼고 있는 거야?
she's shutting us out again?
쉬
Shh.
뭐?
What?
네 말 듣겠다
She can hear you.
자고 있잖아
She's sleeping.
쟤는 알리야
She's Ali.
자는구만
She's sleeping.
고마워, 한나
Thanks, Han.
알리가 사람들이
자신을 돕게 하는 것도 이해가 돼
It makes sense that Ali
had people helping her.
만약 그게 우리였다면
우린 알리와 통화하고 싶을 거야
You know, if it were us,
we'd want her to call.
우린 알리가 안전한지
알고 싶을 거라구
We'd want to know
that she was okay.
바로 그거야, 엠
그게 우리라구
That's the thing, Em.
It is us.
We're the ones who are
risking everything to help her.
우린 알리를 돕기 위해
모든 위험을 무릅쓸 사람들이야
알리가 길을 가다가
아무렇게나 만난
It's not some
random do-gooders
that she's met along the way.
박애주의자가 아니라구
몇 시간만 더
기다리기만 하면 돼
We just have to wait it out
a few more hours.
Once Ezra tells us who "A" is,
에즈라가 우리에게
A가 누구인지 말해주면
this will finally be over.
마침내 끝나는 거지
네가 말하는 것이
신의 귀에 닿기를
From your lips to God's ears.
When did you become religious?
언제부터 종교적이 됐냐?
My mom's dating
a preacher, remember?
우리 엄마가 목사님이랑
데이트하는거 기억 안나?
A가 없는 생활이 어떨지 상상이 가?
Can you imagine what life
would be like without "A"?
When was the last time
you guys had a hobby?
너희들이 취미를 가졌던
마지막이 언제였지?
전혀 없었어
Never.
I wouldn't mind
taking up a sport though.
하지만 운동을 시작하는 것도 괜찮겠지
Which one?
어떤 운동?
I don't know.
나도 몰라
I've always liked
Spencer's field hockey skirt.
나는 늘 스펜서의
필드하키 스커트가 좋았었어
You can totally have it.
넌 완전 할 수 있어
What about you, Spence?
너는 어때, 스펜스?
I wouldn't want
to go back to the person
예전의 나로
돌아가고 싶진 않아
that I was before.
난 이기는 것에만
신경을 썼었어
All I cared about was winning.
And now I just really
want to be happy.
그리고 지금은
정말로 행복해 지고 싶어
(gasps)
어떻게 나를 찾았어요?
How did you find me?
그건, 우린 외모만 비슷한 게 아냐
Well, we don't just look alike.
We think alike, too.
우린 생각하는 것도 같아
여기에 온 건 큰 위험이예요
You took a big risk coming here.
선택의 여지가 없었어
I didn't have a choice.
Alison, you asked
for my help in Ravenswood.
앨리슨, 넌 레이븐스우드에서
내 도움을 청했었지
이제 내가 너의 도움이 필요해
Now I need yours.
그럼 핏츠는 핏츠제럴드였군
So Fitz is a Fitzgerald.
이 일이 될거라 확신해요?
Are you sure this is gonna work?
It has to.
그렇게 돼야 해
난 선택의 여지가 없어
I don't have another choice.
We should be okay
if we do this today.
오늘 밤 이걸 한다면
우린 괜찮을 거야
경찰들은 아직
필라델피아를 뒤지고 있어
The cops are still looking
in Philadelphia.
You having second thoughts?
두 번째 생각은 있는 거야?
없어요
No.
I just realized this might be
the last time I see you.
이번이 당신을 마지막으로
보는 거라는 걸 알았어요
너무 호들갑스럽게 굴지 마, 알리
Don't be so dramatic, Ali.
넌 우리를 알잖아
You know us.
우린 항상 서로에게
돌아갈 길을 찾아낸다구
We always find
a way back to each other.
너희 둘이
키스라도 하는 장면이야?
Is this the part
where you guys kiss?
진작 부탁해 볼 걸
Had to ask.
당신은 가는 것이 낫겠어요
You better get going.
Thank you.
고마워
날 위해서 똑같은 일을
해줬잖아요
You'd do the same for me.
에즈라 핏츠 수술 끝났나요?
Is Ezra Fitz out of surgery?
회복 중이예요
NURSE: He's in recovery.
(sighs)
What are you doing?
뭐하는 거야?
날 깨우겠다고 했잖아
You said that you'd wake me up.
아직 의식이 없지만 안정적이야
He's still unconscious,
but he's stable.
Ezra?
에즈라?
(monitor beeping)
도와주세요!
Help!
여기 도움이 필요해요!
We need some help in here!
Hurry!
급해요!
(indistinct)
코드 블루, 123이 필요하다
MAN (over PA):
Code Blue, we need 123.
어디 갔었어?
EMILY:
Where have you been?
엠, 제발 다른 애들은 깨우지 마
Em, please don't
wake up the others.
우린 모두 여기 함께 있어, 알리
We're all in this together, Ali.
적어도 그게 우리 생각이야
At least that's what we thought.
There are some things
네가 알 필요가 없는
you don't need
to know about, Em.
일들이 있어, 엠
Okay?
알겠지?
It's better that way.
그게 최선이야
That's not a good enough answer.
그건 충분한 답이 아냐
따라 와
Come on.
Some of you may know each other,
너희 중 일부는
서로 아는 사이일 거야
some of you may not.
일부는 그렇지 않을 거고
너희들을 택한 건
But I picked you
우리 모두는 한가지
because we all have one thing
공통점이 있어
in common,
그건 앨리슨 딜로렌티스에 관한 거야
and that's Alison DiLaurentis.
앨리슨이 여기 있을 때
난 모나가 아니었어
When Alison was here,
I wasn't Mona.
난 루저 모나였어
I was Loser Mona.
Who were you, Lucas?
넌 뭐였지, 루카스?
Hermie.
애벌레
음
Hmm.
넌 어땠지, 페이지?
How about you, Paige?
I can say it
if you don't want to.
원치 않으면
내가 말할 수 있어
She called you Pigskin.
앨리슨은 너를
돼지 껍데기라고 불렀어
MAN 1: I was Pus Face.
난 고름 얼굴이었어
난 도룡뇽
MAN 2: I was Newt.
난 레즈
WOMAN 1: Lez.
WOMAN 2: Whore.
난 창녀
하지만 너희들은
그런 사람들이 아니야
But you weren't those people.
That's just what she called you.
단지 앨리슨이 그렇게 부른 것 뿐이지
너희 자신은 아니야
Not who you are.
Sticks and stones, Mona.
말로는 뭘 못하겠어, 모나
난 더이상 그녀가 두렵지 않아
I'm not afraid of her anymore.
Well, maybe you should be.
넌 그럴지도 모르지
그녀는 아직 돌아오지도 않았는데
She's not even back yet,
and she found a way
너와 에밀리를 깨뜨릴 방법을 알았지
to break up you and Emily.
방법이 없어
There's no way.
알리는 너희 둘을
커플이 되게 할 거야
Ali's gonna let you guys
be a couple.
Exactly what is it
you want us to do?
네가 우리에게 원하는 게 정확히 뭔데?
I want us to stick together.
우리가 단결하길 원해
There's strength in numbers.
숫적인 힘이지
The bigger we are,
the harder she falls.
우리가 거대해질 수록
앨리슨은 더 심하게 무너질테니까
I don't think I want
to be a part of this.
난 일원이 되고 싶진 않아
I can't protect you
if you're not with us.
우리와 함께 하지 않는다면
널 보호해 줄 수 없어
우린 시간이 많지 않아
We don't have much time.
Ezra was paying CeCe
for information.
에즈라는 정보를 위해
씨씨를 고용하고 있었어
씨씨가 레이븐스우드에 있었던 이유지
That's why
she was in Ravenswood.
그럼 씨씨는 이전엔
빨간 코트를 입지 않았었어?
So she wasn't ever
really Red Coat?
No, I asked her
to wear that hoping that
그래, A의 주의를 돌리기 위해
코트를 입어 달라고 내가 요청했고
난 시야에서 벗어날 수 있었어
she would distract "A"
so I could turn off the saw.
"A" put you in that box.
Not CeCe.
A 가 그 박스를 둔 거야
씨씨가 그런 게 아니야
She helped me save your life.
씨씨는 나를 도와서
너희 목숨을 구한거야
Why does this have
to be a secret?
왜 이걸 비밀로 하는 거야?
Why can't you tell
the other girls?
왜 다른 아이들에게
말해주지 않는 거지?
CeCe killed a cop, Em,
씨씨는 경찰을 죽였어, 엠
그리고 나를 위해서 했던 부분이야
and part of why she did
that was for me.
Look, if she gets busted
boarding that plane,
만약 그녀가
비행기에 오르다 적발되면
my face is on the passport.
여권엔 내 얼굴이 있어
That makes me an accessory.
그건 나를 공범으로 만드는 거야
그리고 이제 너도 사실을 알게 됐어
And now you know about it.
That makes you one, too.
너 역시 공범이 된 거야
You guys have done
so much for me.
너희들은 나를 위해
너무 많은 일을 해줬어
You do not need to go out
on a limb for CeCe.
너희들이 씨씨를 위해
위험을 무릅쓸 필요는 없어
I will take the fall
for it alone
나 혼자 망가질 거야
if it comes to it.
그런 일이 일어난다면
(footsteps approaching)
Hey, Aria's on the phone,
but we can't hear her.
아리아에게 전화가 왔는데
목소리가 들리지 않아
Tell her to call the house line.
일반 전화로 아리아에게 전화해
(dialing)
Ezra made it through surgery,
에즈라는 수술을 마쳤어
but I haven't been able to...
하지만 아직 알 수 없...
Damn it.
제기랄
(telephone ringing)
여보세요, 내 말 들려?
Hello, can you hear me?
HOLBROOK: Hello?
여보세요?
앨리슨?
Alison?
What is it?
무슨 일이야?
뉴욕 경찰은
웨스트 44번가에 있는
The NYPD needs to send somebody
핏츠제랄드 극장으로
경찰을 보내야 합니다
to the Fitzgerald Theater
on West 44th Street.
I think we have a 10-20
on Alison DiLaurentis.
앨리슨 딜로렌티스가
있다고 생각합니다
Oh, pick up.
아, 받아라
Come on, guys.
Pick up.
제발, 얘들아
전화 받으라구
(telephone ringing)
안녕...
Hey...
you're gonna be okay.
괜찮아 질 거예요
(whispering)
What is it?
왜 그래요?
Did you recognize the voice?
네 목소리를 알아챈 거야?
No.
아니
Okay.
좋아
에즈라가 우리에게
A가 누구인지 말해주길 기다릴 수 없어
We can't wait for Ezra
to tell us who "A" is.
우린 널 공항에 데려가야 해
We have to get you
to the airport.
You can still use that passport
노엘이 준 여권과 비행기표를
and that ticket
that Noel gave you, right?
사용할 수 있는 거지?
I don't have it anymore.
지금은 가지고 있지 않아
What?
뭐라구?
(whispering)
I gave away my get out
of town free card
나보다 더 필요한 사람에게
여기를 벗어날
통행권을 줘 버렸어
to someone who needed it
more than I did.
알리, 지금 너 보다
더 도움이 필요한 사람이 누구야?
Ali, who needs more help
than you do right now?
It doesn't matter.
상관 없어
우린 상관 있어
It does to us.
Look, Ali, either you
trust us or you don't.
알리, 우리를 믿던지 말던지 선택을 해
더 이상 비밀은 없어, 알리
No more secrets, Ali.
You were wrong before.
넌 예전에 잘못한 거야
그들은 우리를
함께 두지 않았다구
They didn't keep us together.
택시 안에서
논쟁을 할 수 있어
We can argue
about this in the cab.
알겠지?
우리 물건 챙겨서 가자
Okay?
Let's grab our stuff and go.
SPENCER: Come on.
빨리
서둘러야 해
EMILY:
But we have to hurry.
Who's out there?
거기 누구야?
Couldn't have picked
a better place
네 이야기를 끝마치는데
더 좋은 장소를 택할 순 없겠는 걸
to end your story.
Shana?
샤나?
I thought I locked you
all together at the lodge.
너희들을 그 산장에
모두 가뒀다고 생각했었지
But I guess you were late
to the party, Alison.
하지만 네가
파티에 늦었다고 생각했거든, 앨리슨
So much for fighting fire
with fire.
화염 속에서
너무 오래 불과 싸웠지
Put the gun down, Shana.
총 내려놔, 샤나
Get back, Spencer.
물러서, 스펜서
Get back.
물러서라구
널 믿었어, 샤나
I trusted you, Shana.
You once told me
the only way to trust
누군가를 믿을 수 있는
유일한 방법은
someone was to not ask
too many questions.
너무 많은 질문을 하지 않는 것이라고
넌 내게 말했었지
And then you sent me
to Rosewood to ask questions.
그리고 너는 질문을 하기 위해
로즈우드로 나를 보냈어
Move.
비켜
샤나
Shana.
왜...
Why...
왜 이렇게 나를 공격하는 거야?
Why would you
turn on me like this?
I got so many answers
from all the people you hurt.
네가 상처 준 모든 사람들에게
많은 답을 들었지
네 자신의 어머니도
널 두려워했어
Your own mother
was afraid of you.
물러나!
Get back!
알리가 잘못했어
Ali's made mistakes,
okay, Shana,
but what makes you better?
그래, 샤나
하지만 네게 무슨 이득이지?
You're sick, Shana.
넌 아픈 거야, 샤나
Like Mona was,
but we can get you help.
모나가 그랬던 것 처럼
하지만 우리가 널 도울 수 있어
난 모나가 아냐
이건 게임이 아니라구
I'm not Mona.
This isn't a game.
그럼 뭐지?
So what is it?
Justice.
정의야
SPENCER: For who?
누굴 위한 정의?
Jenna.
제나
You fell in love with her.
너 제나와 사랑했었구나
You have no idea who she is.
제나가 어떤 애였는지 넌 몰라
We never meant...
우린 절대 고의가...
Get back
or I'll blow your head off!
물러나지 않으면
대가리를 날려 주겠어
What did you call it once, Ali?
한 번은 네가 뭐라고 했더라, 알리?
A happy accident?
행복한 사고?
제나는 널 사랑하지 않았어, 샤나
Jenna doesn't love you, Shana.
She's playing you.
널 갖고 논 거야
That's what she does.
그게 제나가 한 짓이야
No, that's what you do.
아니, 그건 네가 한 짓이지
So what?
그래서 어쩌자는 건데?
She's the mastermind
and you're her henchman?
제나는 조종자고
넌 졸개인 거야?
Jenna doesn't even know
I'm here.
제나는 내가 여기온 것 조차 몰라
And she'll never know.
그리고 그녀는 절대 모를 거야
And once I'm done with you,
그리고 내가 널 처리해 버리면
she can finally
get back to her life.
제나는 마침내
자신의 삶을 되찾는 거지
Hey, Shana!
헤이, 샤나!
(gunshot)
(screaming)
She's dead.
죽었어
You did what
you had to do, okay?
넌 해야할 일을 한 거야, 알겠지?
EMILY:
Spencer's right.
스펜서 말이 맞아
She would have killed all of us.
샤나는 우리 모두를 죽였을 거야
It really is over.
정말로 모두 끝났어
It's over.
- 끝났다구
- 그래
Yeah.
Let's go home.
집에 가자
We can't just leave her here.
여기에 사냐를 그냥 두고 갈 수 없어
There's been an accident.
사고가 있었어요
Enjoy your flight, sir.
즐거운 비행되세요, 선생님
Welcome aboard, Miss Darkbloom.
탑승을 환영합니다, 다크블룸 양
Merci.
감사합니다
(speaking French)
[프랑스어]
Sync & corrections by wilson0804
www.Addic7ed.com